NYSUT Teacher Education Conference Board Files 6174/009
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Teaching as a Profession Legislation-Entrance Exam Announcement, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  Booklet, Invitation to React to Regents Tentative Proposal on Teaching as a Profession and Teacher Competence, march 7, 1980; discussion item for Regents, Preliminary Recommendations from the Regents Conference on Recruitment and Career Expectations for Teaching, February 11, 1981; Comments on the Regents Proposal Entitled "Teaching as a Profession and Teacher Competence," prepared for NYSUT members who will testify at Regents hearings, March 18, 1989; press release, "Regents Require Examination for Teacher Certification Licensing," April 24, 1981; copies of bills submitted for action by the NYS Legislature on Teaching as a Profession, with cover memo to TECB from Jim Kiepper, March 10, 1981
- NTE Material, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  Papers re National Teacher Examination; list of authors
- COTE Conference, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  10/19-20/78. Program; keynote address to NYS Confederated Organizations for Teacher Education, October 19, 1978; Speech for Delivery at COTE Meeting, by William E. Boyd, "Assessment of Approved CBTE Programs," October 20, 1978; Address to NYS Confederated Organizations for Teacher Education, by Kristi R. Hanson (aide to Sen. Jacob Javits), "How Teacher Educators Can Participate in the Development of National Legislative Policy," October 19, 1978; summary of panel discussion, "How Teacher Educators Can Influence State Legislation"; handwritten notes
- TECB Newsletters/Minutes, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Minutes of March 1, 1978, meeting; typed and handwritten obituary; TECB newsletters, vol. 1, nos. 4 and 8 (spring-summer 1979); newsletter, Education U.S.A, by National School Public Relations Association, December 26, 1977; enrollment information for colleges in NYS, fall 1977
- Women's Educational Equity Act Program Annual Report, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Bound volume from U.S. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, September 30, 1978
- Library Acquisitions, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Selected lists from NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services
- Roslyn Herman TECB, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  State Education Department draft documents re setting standards and improving pupil competency in basic skills, with cover letter, May 16, 1978; article in Phi Delta Kappan, "The Coming Teacher Shortage," June 1978; TECB meeting agenda for May 18, 1978; TECB proposed policy paper on a state plan for inservice education, May 1978
- Inservice Policy Papers, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Proposed agenda for TECB meeting of September 25, 1980; membership list 1980-81; constitution; description of TECB; topics for future position papers; TECB Policy Paper on a State Plan for Inservice Education for K-12 School Personnel, June 1978; The Role of Higher Education in K-12 Inservice: Policy Paper; NYSUT Working paper on Inservice Education, 7/19/77, approved by Executive Committee, 12/8/78; NYSUT Proposed Position Paper on Inservice Education, April 1979; handwritten notes
- The Dean's Signature (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Signature of Daniel E. Griffiths
- TECB Interviews-C. Santelli, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Paper, "Comprehensive Early Childhood Services: Federal Legislation - Yes or No?" by Judith Coburn, December 6, 1977; Coburn vita; vita of Karen S. Davison
- TECB Executive Board, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Minutes and agenda of February 8, 1977, meeting; proposal for summer employment of staff consultant; outline for meeting with Commissioner Ambach, July 20, 1977
- Finance Proposal, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Document, Teacher Education Improvement Program; capitation proposal, with cover letter to TECB staff consultant Patricia Orrange from dean of Syracuse University School of Education, October 17